Guide to the NCAA Volunteers for Youth Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
NCAA Volunteers for Youth records
1970-1984
SC0413
NCAA Volunteers for Youth.
0.75 Linear feet
Records include procedures, volunteer-youth match-up records, evaluations, applications, and newsletters.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The NCAA Volunteers for Youth, which began at Stanford University in 1969 as the Stanford Youth Program, paired student athletes with area middle and high school children who were experiencing academic difficulties or personal problems. The NCAA picked up sponsorship of the program in 1977.
Description of the Collection
Records include procedures, volunteer-youth match-up records, evaluations, applications, and newsletters.
Access Terms
NCAA Volunteers for Youth.; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Stanford University. Stanford Youth Program.; College athletes.; Student volunteers in social service--California; Youth --Services for --California.
Collection Contents
- Records, 1970-1984
  - Third Ed. Handbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fourth Ed. Handbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - First of the Year Operations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Operations: Throughout the Year, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Articles and Quotes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - End of the Year Operations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Samples, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Activities List, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Seminar, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Seminar, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Match-Ups I, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Match-Ups II, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Evaluation Forms, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Board, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Thank You Letter, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Match-Ups I, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Match-Ups II, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Participant List, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Match-Ups, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Memoirs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Match-Ups I, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Match-Ups II, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Match-Ups III, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Volunteer Questionnaire Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Parent-Youth Interview Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Student-Athlete Interview Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Release Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Counselor to Parent Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Address Request Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Parent Evaluation Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Counselor Evaluation Form, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Follow-Up Sheets, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)